{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following from a blood clot stimulates the growth of cells in the healing process?", "opta": "EGF", "optb": "PDGF", "optc": "MPF", "optd": "NGF", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The spindle forms in the", "opta": "G1 phase", "optb": "G2 phase", "optc": "M phase", "optd": "S phase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which phase of mitosis is associated with chromosomes aligned at the center of the cell and centromeres divide?", "opta": "anaphase", "optb": "interphase", "optc": "metaphase", "optd": "prophase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The event(s) which does not occur during interphase, is/are", "opta": "Chromatin condenses", "optb": "Protein Synthesis", "optc": "Organelles replication", "optd": "DNA replication", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In prokaryotes, just before the cell divides, the two daughter genomes are attached side by side to the", "opta": "cell membrane", "optb": "replication origin", "optc": "centromeres", "optd": "equatorial plate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the cell cycle replication of the genome occurs in the", "opta": "G1 phase", "optb": "G2 phase", "optc": "M phase", "optd": "S phase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At which of the following check point, mitosis is controlled?", "opta": "G1", "optb": "G2", "optc": "M", "optd": "S", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The centromeres move toward the poles in __________ .", "opta": "anaphase", "optb": "interphase", "optc": "metaphase", "optd": "prophase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which phase of mitosis is associated with separation of chromatids?", "opta": "Prophase", "optb": "Metaphase", "optc": "Anaphase", "optd": "Telophase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sequences that correctly describes the cell cycle is", "opta": "-> G1-> G2 -> S -> mitosis -> cytokinesis ->", "optb": "-> S -> G2 -> mitosis -> cytokinesis -> G1 ->", "optc": "-> G1 ->S -> G2 -> cytokinesis -> mitosis ->", "optd": "->cytokinesis-> mitosis -> G1 -> S -> G2 ->", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following triggers the division of activated T lymphocytes?", "opta": "FGF", "optb": "Interlukin 2", "optc": "PDGF", "optd": "Erythroprotein", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The term, not related to mitosis is", "opta": "gametes", "optb": "chromosomes", "optc": "DNA replication", "optd": "somatic cells", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What structure forms as a network of protein cables during cell division?", "opta": "Spindle", "optb": "Aster", "optc": "Kinetochore", "optd": "Chromatid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A centromere is", "opta": "another name for kinetochore", "optb": "the structure to which microtubules attach", "optc": "a constriction on a chromosome bound to a disk", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements about mitosis is incorrect?", "opta": "The daughter nuclei are genetically identical to the parent nucleus", "optb": "Chromosomes separate during anaphase due to the interaction of polar microtubules from opposite poles pushing against each other", "optc": "Chromosomes separate during anaphase when the kinetochore microtubules shorten as they depolymerize", "optd": "Chromosomes move to the metaphase plate using motor proteins, a kind of kinesin, attached to spindle fibers", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cdks bind with __________ , enabling the Cdks to function as enzymes.", "opta": "MPF", "optb": "cyclins", "optc": "histones", "optd": "p53", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a part of a human chromosome in any phase?", "opta": "Centriole", "optb": "Histone", "optc": "Nucleosome", "optd": "Centromere", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During which phase, a cleavage furrow is formed in animal cells?", "opta": "C", "optb": "G1", "optc": "G2", "optd": "M", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which phase, each chromosome replicates to produce two sister chromatids?", "opta": "Anaphase", "optb": "Interphase", "optc": "Metaphase", "optd": "Prophase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Microtubules grow from the poles to kinetochores of each chromatid during", "opta": "prophase", "optb": "metaphase", "optc": "anaphase", "optd": "telophase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the normal cell cycle, primarily regulated at checkpoints?", "opta": "Metaphase in mitosis", "optb": "Anaphase, G1 boundary", "optc": "G1-S boundary", "optd": "S-G2 boundary", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The phase of mitosis which is associated with the formation of the nuclear envelope, is", "opta": "prophase", "optb": "metaphase", "optc": "anaphase", "optd": "telophase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At the __________ checkpoint, cell growth is controlled.", "opta": "C", "optb": "G1", "optc": "G2", "optd": "S", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A nuclear envelope forms around each set of sister chromatids in", "opta": "anaphase", "optb": "metaphase", "optc": "prophase", "optd": "telophase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which of the following phase preparations for genome separation are made?", "opta": "C", "optb": "G1", "optc": "G2", "optd": "M", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cells which no longer divide (such as certain specialized cells found in the human brain) remain in which phase of the cell cycle?", "opta": "Prophase", "optb": "S phase", "optc": "G0 Phase", "optd": "Gl Phase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cell cycle is controlled in most cells by", "opta": "time (after a certain length of time the cell divides)", "optb": "a series of checkpoints", "optc": "cell size (when the cell reaches a certain size, it divides)", "optd": "different cells exhibit different control strategies", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many chromatids does a diploid body cell contain just prior to cell division?", "opta": "23", "optb": "46", "optc": "69", "optd": "92", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA replication is controlled at which of the following checkpoint?", "opta": "G1", "optb": "G2", "optc": "M", "optd": "S", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following begins when pairs of sister chromatids align in the center of the cell?", "opta": "Anaphase", "optb": "Interphase", "optc": "Metaphase", "optd": "Prophase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many chromatids are there in a duplicated chromosome?", "opta": "One", "optb": "Two", "optc": "Three", "optd": "Four", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The term homologous chromosomes", "opta": "refers to replications of the same chromosome", "optb": "is another name for sister chromatids", "optc": "must be haploid", "optd": "means a pair of chromosomes of the same kind, such as sex chromosomes", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At the center of the cell cycle control system is Cdk, a protein that", "opta": "is phosphorylated to become active", "optb": "binds to different cyclins", "optc": "is only active during mitosis", "optd": "manufactures growth factors", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Each chromosome contains two chromatids by the end of the __________ phase in the life cycle of a human cell.", "opta": "C", "optb": "G2", "optc": "M", "optd": "S", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the primary growth phase of a cell?", "opta": "G1", "optb": "G2", "optc": "M", "optd": "G0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The G0 phase is", "opta": "a permanent state of all body cells", "optb": "the state of most cells in an animal body", "optc": "another name for interphase", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}